A Guide to the Contents of the Huff Lane Elementary School Time Capsule 1949-1950
Roanoke Public Libraries
Roanoke Public Libraries
A Guide to the Contents of the Huff Lane Elementary School Time Capsule
Roanoke Public Libraries
2014.6.18
1 record storage box
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by the City of Roanoke
Historical Note
Huff Lane Elementary was located in the northwestern part of Roanoke City and was named after the farm of Peter Huff, which dominated the area. The Huff Lane School operated from 1950 to 2010 when it was closed due to the budget. The school was razed in 2014 after the property was sold in February of that year to NDRA II, LLC to make room for commercial development in the Valley View Mall area. According a Roanoke Times article from April 2014, a Roanoke citizen that remembered the 1950 ceremony, made a call to alert the demolition crew that a time capsule was in the foundation somewhere. A worker later found the sealed metal box among the debris.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of 1 record storage box and the time capsule. The materials contained in this collection are varied, but include different reports and pamphlets associated with the city and the schools. The collection includes several newspaper sections, small stamps, coins, brochures, reports, and directories. The collection focuses specifically on 1949-1950 to commemorate the year the time capsule was sealed within the Huff Lane cornerstone, while there are a few items that fall outside of that time range, most are from 1950. While the collection provides a fairly well-rounded perspective of 1950s Roanoke, it does not include photographs from the time. Perhaps the most interesting piece is the Chamber of Commerce statistical report. It details remarkable facts about Roanoke in a relatively short document.
Arrangement
Documents are arranged by document type.
Contents List
- Contents of the Huff Lane Elementary School Time Capsule (Box 1)
  - Artifacts - Coins, Stamps and a Small Tin Container 1950 (Folder 1)
  - Book - Roanoke: Story of County and City 1942 (Folder 2)
  - Directory - Students enrolled in Oakland Elementary and William Fleming High 1949-1950 (Folder 3)
  - Directory - Roanoke City Schools 1949-1950 (Folder 4)
  - Directory - Roanoke-Salem Phone Directory 1949 (Folder 5)
  - Directory - Roanoke-Salem-Vinton Industrial Directory 1950 (Folder 6)
  - Newspaper - The Roanoke Times 11 June 1950 (Folder 7-11)
  - Map - City of Roanoke Showing Area Schools 1949 (Folder 12)
  - Pamphlet - Avisco News, The American Viscose Corporation 1950 (Folder 13)
  - Magazine - Norfolk and Western Magazine 1950 (Folder 14)
  - Pamphlet - School Building Bond Program 1949 (Folder 15)
  - Pamphlet - Roanoke Tourism circa 1949 (Folder 16)
  - Pamphlet - Traffic Laws of Roanoke 1947 (Folder 17)
  - Program - Cornerstone Laying Ceremony and Contents List 11 June 1950 (Folder 18)
  - Report - Chamber of Commerce Statistical Report 1950 (Folder 19)
  - Report - City Budget 1950 (Folder 20)
  - Report - City Goverment Directory and Financials 1949 (Folder 21)
  - Report - School Budget 1950 (Folder 22)
  - Report - School Building Program 1949-1954 (Folder 23)
- Huff Lane Elementary School Time Capsule (Box 2)